Kyle Bini

A full stack software engineer with a design background. My previous career as a landscape designer has been invaluable in my engineering education to allow me to visualize and develop creative solutions to problems, while grounding me in the development process.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Boston, MA (Remote) — *Software Engineering Immersive*

MAY 2020 - AUGUST 2020

Developed four projects during a 12-week (500+ hrs) immersive program in software engineering. Engaged in fast-paced, meaningful lessons to explore full stack applications, programs and frameworks. Projects focused on developing single-page applications in a RESTful style.

Back in 10! - A calendar application designed to promote wellness activities during daily life (*React.js*, *Express.js*, *Axios*, *Bootstrap*)

PlusOne – (Team Project) A social event application allowing users to post an event they are attending and allow other users to RSVP (*React.js*, *Express.js*, *Axios*, *SASS*)

Take A Hike! - A tracking application allowing users to create and log hikes (*JavaScript*, *Express.js*, *Ajax*, *SASS*)

D.A. Dunlevy, Poolesville, MD — Landscape Designer

NOVEMBER 2015 - FEBRUARY 2020

- Developed and managed projects from initial site analysis through conceptual development, schematic plans and detailed construction documentation.
- Maintained multiple projects simultaneously at varying stages from inception to completion.
- Built and fostered client relationships as the main point person on upwards of 12 projects at a time.
- Managed install crews, oversaw project layout and installation throughout the construction process.

Caesars Entertainment Corp., Atlantic City, NJ — CRM Coordinator

JANUARY 2015 - NOVEMBER 2015

- Built customer offers for targeted audiences and manipulated mail files for all direct mail and email campaigns.
- Executed project tasks independently and as part of a team to meet tight deadlines and send offers on time, within scope and on budget.
 Performed QA on all materials for errors and accuracy.
- Managed several projects simultaneously and coordinated with departments nationwide to track and organize each project stage.

• New Jersey, 08520

(609) 558-5331

kbini28@gmail.com

kbini28.github.io

in linkedin.com/in/kylebini

github.com/kbini28

LANGUAGES, FRAMEWORKS & SKILLS

React.js JavaScript

CSS/SASS Bootstrap

HTML Node.js

Express.js Python

MongoDB Mongoose

Django PostgreSQL

Github jQuery

Ajax Axios

Heroku Handlebars

DESIGN SKILLS

Illustrator Photoshop

InDesign Vectorworks

EDUCATION

Delaware Valley University Doylestown, PA B.S. Environmental Design

Graduated 2013

ORGANIZATIONS

Sigma Nu Fraternity

Primary Charitable
Organization –
Susan G. Komen Breast
Cancer Foundation